Guide to the Wilder Bancroft papers, 1896-1953.
Bancroft, Wilder papers, 1896-1953
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Wilder Bancroft papers, 1896-1953.
14-8-135
Wilder D. (Wilder Dwight) Bancroft, 1867-1953.
10.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, student reports, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Personal correspondence; professional correspondence relating to electrochemistry, physical chemistry, pandemic chemistry, cloud dispersal and rainmaking, and other chemical studies; student reports; materials relating to professional societies; records relating to the John Bancroft Estate; and other miscellaneous professional papers.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Wilder D. Bancroft was professor of chemistry at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Personal correspondence; professional correspondence relating to electrochemistry, physical chemistry, pandemic chemistry, cloud dispersal and rainmaking, and other chemical studies; student reports; materials relating to professional societies; records relating to the John Bancroft Estate; and other miscellaneous professional papers.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bancroft, Wilder D. (Wilder Dwight), 1867-1953.; Bancroft, John.; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
Chemistry--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Biographical material (Box 1)
- Misc. personal material (Box 1)
- Biographies of other scientists (Box 1)
- Professional societies (Box 1)
- Degrees and honorary memberships (Box 1)
- Photographs (Box 2)
- Financial and legal papers
  - Patents (Box 3)
  - Contracts and power of attorney (Box 3)
  - Personal and domestic bills for the year 1916 (Box 3)
- John Bancroft estate
  - Management and settlement of the estate (Box 4)
  - "Japanese goods" material (Box 4)
- Journal of Physical Chemistry
  - W.D. Bancroft, editor and co-founder, 1897 (Box 5)
  - Financial records, 1921-1925 (Box 5)
- Pandemic Chemistry: research and lecture material arranged according to outline of Pandemic Chemistry course
  - General information and lectures (Box 6)
  - Lectures (Box 7)
  - Lectures (Box 8)
  - Swarthmore lectures (Box 8)
  - Westbrook lectures (Box 8)
  - Marshall Field lectures (Box 8)
- Lecture books
  - Colloid chemistry, 1911-1931 (Box 9)
  - Mass law, 1896-1900 (Box 9)
- Lectures and notebooks
  - Electrochemistry, 1895-1930 (Box 10)
  - Physical chemistry, 1905-1935 (Box 10)
- Graduate and research work
  - Abrasives (Box 11)
  - Quicksand (Box 11)
  - Misc. reports (Box 11)
- Misc. research reports (Box 12)
- Industrial research reports and professional opinions (Box 13)
- Student's lab research reports, 1912-1913 (Box 14)
- Misc. notebooks and catalogues (Box 14)
- Research in charcoal (Box 15)
- Copy (Box 15)
- Pamphlets on anthocyanins (Box 15)
- Book: "Luther Burbank" by W.D.B. (Box 15)
- Cloud dispersal and rain making: correspondence and research materials (Box 16)
- Copy for pamphles, "Heredity and Environment" by W.D.B. (Box 17)
- Misc. physical chemistry (papers, notes, graphs) (Box 18)
- Misc. colloid and electro chemistry (notes, papers, graphs) (Box 19)
- Pamphlets and magazines (Box 20)
- Record of the work done in the laboratory of applied physiology (Box 21)
- Correspondence
  - pre-1900, 1902-1904 (Box 22)
  - 1905-1906 (Box 23)
  - 1907-1909, A-C (Box 24)
  - 1909, D-H (Box 25)
  - 1910, A-W (Box 26)
  - 1911-1913, A-M (Box 27)
  - 1913, N-Z (Box 28)
  - 1914-1915 (Box 29)
  - 1916 (Box 30)
  - 1917-1920 (Box 31)
  - 1921-1922 (Box 32)
  - 1923-1925 (Box 33)
  - 1926-1930 (Box 34)
  - 1931-1932 (Box 35)
  - 1933-1953 and undated (Box 36)
- Accounts (Box 37)
- Other material (Box 38)